{
    "id": "8634dd288fa343eeaf0e83e6921c57d0",
    "title": "Gerunds and infinitives",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "29928ae4bcde49dab3f08140b477ff2e",
            "title": "Gerunds And Infinitives",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "I hope you don’t mind ……………………….. leaving early.",
                    "description": "Gerund is a noun equivalent. It can only be modified by a possessive adjective.",
                    "answers": [
                        "me",
                        "my",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "We are prevented ………………………….. to him.",
                    "description": "Prevent is followed by from + ing form.",
                    "answers": [
                        "to talk",
                        "from talking",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The teacher encouraged us …………………………… harder.",
                    "description": "Encourage is followed by to + infinitive.",
                    "answers": [
                        "to working",
                        "working",
                        "to work"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I am tired ………………………….",
                    "description": "Tired is followed by of + ing form.",
                    "answers": [
                        "to walk",
                        "of walking",
                        "to walking"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "We rejoiced at …………………………. winning.",
                    "description": "Gerund is a noun equivalent. It can only be modified by a possessive adjective.",
                    "answers": [
                        "him",
                        "his",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "We heard of …………………………. having won another trophy.",
                    "description": "Gerund is a noun equivalent. It can only be modified by a possessive adjective.",
                    "answers": [
                        "him",
                        "his",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "He insisted on ………………………. being present at the meeting.",
                    "description": "Gerund is a noun equivalent. It can only be modified by a possessive adjective.",
                    "answers": [
                        "my",
                        "me",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "All depends on ………………………… getting the job.",
                    "description": "Gerund is a noun equivalent. It can only be modified by a possessive adjective.",
                    "answers": [
                        "him",
                        "his",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "We left without …………………………. knowing.",
                    "description": "Gerund is a noun equivalent. It can only be modified by a possessive expression.",
                    "answers": [
                        "anyone",
                        "anyone's",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "You are expected ………………………… work at 8 am every morning.",
                    "description": "Expect is followed by an object + infinitive.",
                    "answers": [
                        "starting",
                        "to start"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Why don’t you let me ………………………..?",
                    "description": "Let is followed by object + infinitive without to. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "speaking",
                        "to speak",
                        "speak"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I recommend you ……………………….. this coat.",
                    "description": "Recommend can be followed by object + to infinitive or noun clause.\r\n",
                    "answers": [
                        "to buy",
                        "buy",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}